# Jacob Nathanson

# Web Developer

317 6th ave, Brooklyn, NY, 11215

jacobnath93@gmail.com

347.489.2611

## Objective

Recent Bootcamp graduate with over 3 years of experience in Education. Patient and resilient problem solver seeking to obtain a challenging position that utilizes current knowledge of web development and design. Positive outlook and team player.

#### **Skills**

HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript (ES6), React, React Native, Bootstrap, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, git, GitHub, VS Code.

### **Personal Projects**

# Dreamy - (live site - github)

A dream journal app built with the MERN stack, allowing users to perform CRUD operations on their journal entries. Uses passport, JSON web-tokens, and Google Oauth to authenticate users.

#### Banh Mi Mami - (github)

React Native app to order Vietnamese food from a fictional local restaurant. Utilizes Redux Toolkit to control and update menu items, user information, and shopping cart.

# NYC Foodies' Trucks - (live site - github)

React single-page application used to explore fictional local food trucks and order catering. Utilizes bootstrap for design and redux toolkit for state management.

#### **Education**

- Full-Stack Web & Mobile Development,

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures,

- Responsive Web Design

- BA Psychology & Music

NuCamp 2021-2022

FreeCodeCamp - 2020

FreeCodeCamp - 2020

University of Michigan - 2011-2015

# **Other Experiences**

#### Magic Ears/ ESL Teacher

APRIL 2020-DECEMBER 2021, REMOTE

- Conducted 30-minute online English lessons for classes of 1-4 Chinese students per session.
- Consistently ranked above 90% approval from student and parent rankings.

#### Fisher's SuperKids/ ESL Teacher

AUGUST 2019- MARCH 2020 DA NANG, VIETNAM

- Taught English lessons for Vietnamese students ages 5 18, with classes averaging between 10-15 students.
- Provided weekly video-speaking challenges to review material and produce language in real-world scenarios.
- Help build confidence in students through team-building exercises and collaborative projects.

#### Vietnam USA Society/ ESL Teacher

FEBRUARY 2018-AUGUST 2020 HCMC, VIETNAM

- Taught English lessons for Vietnamese students ages 5 18, with classes averaging between 18-20 students.
- Assisted in leading extra-curricular speaking challenges and events to increase pupils' motivation.